《カブト：ここまで僕の
手駒を減らされるとはね。
I didn't expect to lose
this many of my pawns...
特殊死体の回収も
失敗に終わったし→
Furthermore,
retrieving unique corpses
turned out to be a failure...
さて　次の手は…》
So then, what's my next move?
((口寄せ穢土転生の術？
Summoning... Reanimation Jutsu?
（大蛇丸）もとは
二代目火影が開発した術。
The Second Hokage
originally developed it.
でも　彼は禁術として封印したの。
But he sealed it away
as a Forbidden Jutsu.
もったいないんで
私が復活させてあげたのよ。
That was such a waste,
so I restored it.
大蛇丸様が
人の術に惚れ込んだのですか。
You became enamored by
another's jutsu, Lord Orochimaru?
これ便利よ。　もっとも　二代目の
術からは　だいぶ改良したけれど。
It's very convenient, you know.
Naturally, I've made
quite a few improvements
from the Second Hokage's
original jutsu.
でも　まだまだ
改良の余地があるし→
But there's still much
I can do with it.
それに　個人情報物質が必要なの。
And I must have more materials
containing individual data.
個人情報物質？
Materials containing
individual data?
なんのことです？
What do you mean?
つまり　血や肉よ。
Oh, like blood and flesh...
伝説となるような忍の。
from legendary shinobi.
それなりには集めてきたけど。
I've collected what I could, but...
これからは　あなたにも
手伝ってもらうわ。
From now on,
you can help me.
そして　この術を完成させるのよ。
We shall perfect this jutsu.
(わかりました　大蛇丸様))
I understand, Lord Orochimaru.
戦場をひっかきまわしてみるかな。
Maybe I'll stir things up
on the battlefield.
softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
The Reanimated Allied Forces
（ムサイ）あれは　味方か？
（ノノタ）そうだよ。
Are they... allies?!
Yes!
お～い！
Hey!
穢土転生の封印か。
ああ。
A Sealed Reanimation?
Yeah...
雲の磁遁使いトロイさんだ。
That's Toroi,
the Cloud's Magnet-Style User.
よく　アンタら２人でやれたな。
I'm amazed that just the two of you
managed to seal him.
エヘヘッ　実は　ナルトさんが
助けに来てくれたんだよ。
No, actually...
Naruto came to help us.
名のある忍も穢土転生で
操られちゃ浮かばれねえな。
The famed shinobi who was being
controlled by the Reanimation...
He must be turning in his grave.
俺の親父は　トロイさんと
一緒に任務に出て死んだんだ。
My dad went on a mission
with Toroi and was killed...
え　そうだったの？
Huh? No kidding?
親父には
荷が勝ちすぎたんだろうが。
The burden was probably
too much for my dad.
おい　見ろ　あそこ。
Hey, look over there!
（ムサイ）穢土転生忍者か
まだいやがったな。
A Reanimated Ninja!
There's still another one!
さっさと封印しよう。
We have to seal him immediately!
（トルネ）口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu.
そんな…。
これほどの伏兵が…。
What the—?!
It's a huge ambush...!
本部へ増援を要請しろ。
はい。
Contact HQ for reinforcements!
R-Right!
まさか　キミたちを
戦場に出すはめになろうとはね。
To think I'd have to
resort to sending in
you guys into the battlefield...
命令だ。　封印された
穢土転生忍者を奪還する。
Our orders are to take back
the Reanimated Ninja
who have been sealed.
（ダイマル）なに仕切ってんだよ。
木ノ葉の下にはつかねえぞ。
Don't order me around!
I won't listen to a Leaf Ninja!
（中覚）よしなされ。　わしらは
もはや現世の立場は関係ない。
Enough...
We are no longer part
of the transient world.
（ヘイジ）忌々しいが　皆同じ命令で
縛られた　ひとつの部隊だな。
It's annoying,
but we're all being controlled
and under the same orders.
号令は俺が出す。　全軍　突撃用意！
I'm giving the orders!
All units prepare to attack!
誰だ　お前。
フン。
Who the hell are you?
赤き砂塵　風のダイマル。
The Red Cloud of Dust...
Daimaru of the Wind!
さすがに知ってるらしいな。
So you know me!
知らねえな。
I don't know you.
お前　きっと俺より先に
死んでたんだよ！
You must've died before me!
とにかくだ　操られてる以上
どうにもならねえ。
Anyway!
We're being controlled and there's
nothing we can do about that!
やるにせよ　やられるにせよ
さっさと　ケリつけるぞ。
Whether we kill or get killed,
let's get it over with!
（オソイ）俺は　やられたくないがな。
I don't wanna die...
ゴチャゴチャうるせえんだよ！
Stop the quibbling!
全部隊　進め！
All units, attack!
数は　こっちが遥かに上だ。
We have the advantage in numbers!
き　きた。
構えろ！
H-Here they come...
On guard!
あれじゃ　まるで
穢土転生忍者の→
That's like
an Allied Force-sized army
忍連合軍じゃないか！
of Reanimated Ninja!
あんなのに来られたら
俺たち　ダメかも…。
I-If we come
face to face with them...
it's probably over for us...
かかれ～！
Attack!
おい　下がれ！
来るな　来るな～！！
Hey, get back!
Don't come! Stay away!
うわぁ　やばいぞ！！
Hey, this is bad!
コイツら　弱い…。
They're... weak.
下忍クラスじゃないのか？
Maybe they're only genin.
ダメだ　ダメだ！
It's no good! It's no good!
誰だよ
数は上だからって言ったのは！
Who said we had the advantage?!
突撃！
封印班も前へ！
Attack!
Sealing Team, advance!
いける。
（ノノタ）封印だ　封印だ！
We can do this!
Seal them! Seal them!
あの穢土転生たち　まさか…。
Don't tell me
those Reanimations are...
((いくつも転生させたけど→
I reanimated a lot of them...
個人情報物質を集めるのは
大変だったよ。
But gathering individual data
is hard work.
それってつまり
死体探しだからね。
You're literally looking
for dead bodies.
腐って誰だかわかりゃしない。
And you can't tell who they are
when they're rotting...
(失敗作もいくつも作った))
I had lots of failures.
その　失敗作なの？
And they're the failures?
敵は　数だけだ！　一気に行くぞ！
The enemy's only strength
is in numbers!
We attack in one sweep!
（オソイ）ムサイ！
Musai?!
お前　ムサイか！？
Are you... Musai?!
まさか…　親父！？
ええ～！
Don't tell me...
Dad?!
Huh?!
アンタの親父！？　強いの？
Your dad?!
Is he strong?
中忍…　止まりだったよな　親父。
You didn't get past chunin class,
right, Dad?
ばかもん！
嘘でも強かったと言え！
You fool!
Say I was strong,
even if you have to lie!
あれだ。
There!
あっ　こっちくるぞ！
They're coming this way!
狙いは　トロイだ！
They're after Toroi!
何だ！？
気をつけろ　ムサイ。
What?!
Be careful, Musai.
わしらの役目は…。
Our duty is...
取られた大駒を取り返す。
Taking back my powerful pieces
that I've lost.
そのための捨て駒だ。
That's what you sacrificial pieces
are for...
((なっ　なんだ！？
W-What happened?!
これ　違うわよ　カブト。
This is... not right, Kabuto.
違いますね。　大蛇丸様。
I agree, Lord Orochimaru.
お前たちは　いったい？
Who the hell are you guys?!
一応　尋ねるけど→
I'll ask just in case...
キミ　磁遁使いのトロイじゃないよね？
You aren't the Magnet-Style User
Toroi, are you?
そんな　トロイさんは
わしなんか足元にも及ばぬ。
Are you kidding me?
I can't hold a candle to Toroi.
どうします？　大蛇丸様。
What shall we do, Lord Orochimaru?
(（大蛇丸）とりあえず
とっときましょうか))
Let's keep him for now.
悪いが　逆らうことはできん。
Sorry, I can't disobey.
妙な話だが　トロイさんを助け出す。
As strange as it sounds,
I'm going to rescue Toroi.
絶対に渡さん。　守るんだ！
Absolutely not! We'll protect him!
あそこだ！
Over there!
連絡のあった　穢土転生の部隊だ。
That's the reanimated force
we got the report about!
気を引き締めてかかれ！
Stay focused and attack!
よかった　増援だ！
All right! Reinforcements!
あれは…　まさか！
Is that...? No way.
お～い　俺だ　アニキ！
Huh?!
Hey! It's me, Bro!
俺だ～！
It's me!
お前　なんで？
穢土転生されたの？　お前が？
You? How come?!
Were you reanimated?!
俺の家族は　どうしてる？
子どもらは？
How's my family? My kids?
みんな　無事だ。
里で元気にしている。
They're all fine!
They're doing well in the village.
そうか　元気か。
Good... They're all okay...
お前の嫁さんも
再婚して幸せにやっている。
Your wife remarried
and she's happy!
え！？　アイツ　再婚したの？
Huh? She got remarried?!
仕方ないけどさ…。
I guess that can't be helped.
身内で悪いが　封印するぞ。
I hate to do this to my own kin,
but I have to seal you.
あっ　おい！　俺だ　俺だよ。
Huh? Hey! It's me! It's me!
えっ　なんで？
Huh? What the hell?!
なんで　お前
穢土転生されてんの？
Why'd you let yourself
get reanimated?!
これまで死んでも言えなかったが
俺が悪かったんだ。　許してくれ！
I couldn't say it until now...
But I was wrong. Forgive me!
あっ　そうか。　いや　もういいよ
過ぎたことだから。
Huh? Oh well, forget it.
It's all in the past
and you're dead.
お前も死んだんだし。
許してくれるのか？
You'll forgive me?
とっくに許してたさ！
そうか。
I forgave you long ago...
Really?!
親父　すまないが封印するぞ！
Dad, I'm sorry,
but I have to seal you.
待て！　その前に…。
なに？
Wait! Before that...!
俺は　トロイさんと一緒に
最後まで戦い抜いたのだ。
What is it?
I fought alongside Toroi
until the very end...
里のために！
for the sake of the village!
それを雷影様に伝えてくれ！
Please make sure
you tell Lord Raikage!
親父　わかった。
All right, Dad, I will.
また増援が来たぞ！
More reinforcements are here!
だいぶ集まってきたな。
There's quite a few of them.
このまま引きつけておけ。
あとは任せろ。
Keep them occupied.
Leave the rest to me...
巻き煙の術！
Swirling Smoke Jutsu!
煙だ！
かまうな！　かかれ！
Smoke!
Never mind! Attack!
よし　小隊は俺に続け！
The platoon will follow me!
だから　仕切んなっての！
I said not to order me around!
How tragic...
しかし　無念じゃ。
戦いたくもないのに→
To be forced to fight when
there is no desire to fight.
戦わされるとは。
アイツらは　無念を晴らしたんだな。
They... made peace with themselves.
誰のことだ？
Who are you referring to?
（ダイマル）さっきの
雲のおっさんたちだ。
Those guys from the Cloud...
死ぬ前に言いたかったことを
今更でも言えたんだから。
They were able
to clear their conscience...
after such a long a time.
おぬしも未練がおありか？
Do you have any regrets?
俺　この若さで死んでんだぜ。
ないほうがおかしいだろ。
I died when I was so young...
Wouldn't it be strange
if I didn't have regrets?
そういうことなら俺だって！
Well then, so do I...!
坊さんは？
死は　さだめであろう。
What about you, priest?
Death is one's destiny.
悟ってるな。
You're quite enlightened.
生前は　そうもいかなんだが
おぬしは？
But not during my lifetime.
What about you?
己に未練などなかったが→
I felt no lingering
attachments in life.
そうだな
逆に今なら未練を感じる。
Although now that I'm dead...
I do feel some regret...
未練とは
おもしろいことを言うね　キミたち。
Regrets? What a funny thing
for you guys to talk about...
だが　そんなつもりで
穢土転生させたわけじゃないから。
However, I didn't reanimate you
for such discussions.
((ただいま戻りました。
I've just returned.
首尾は？
How did it go?
岩隠れ
爆遁のガリに間違いありません。
There's no mistake.
It's Gari, the Explosive-Style User
from the Hidden Stone.
（サスケ）また死体あさりか？
Rummaging for corpses again?
せめて墓泥棒と
言ってもらいたいね。
At least call it "grave-robbing."
死んだ者の力に頼るとはな。
Whatever. You're still just
exploiting the dead.
サスケ君　よしなさい。
Don't... Sasuke.
ご苦労だったわね　カブト。
はっ。
Good work, Kabuto.
Yes.
さっさと行くぞ　大蛇丸。
今日は　何をやらせるつもりだ？
Okay, I'm ready, Orochimaru.
What are you making me do today?
(そう焦らないで。
今日の修業は特別よ))
Don't be so hasty.
Today's training will be special.
《大蛇丸様が倒されて
僕は　また一人になった。
Lord Orochimaru was killed...
And I was alone once again.
だが…》
However...
((だが僕は
大蛇丸様を超えようとせず→
However, I never tried to
surpass Lord Orochimaru.
ただ　その力に
すがりついてただけだ。
I simply clung onto his power.
今なら　キミの気持が
本当にわかるよ。
I understand how you felt now.
僕は　キミに気づかされた。
You made me realize something.
僕もキミのようになりたいと思えた。
You made me realize that
I wanted to be like you.
だから今度は　この体に取り込んだ
大蛇丸様を超え→
So this time, I'm going to
surpass Lord Orochimaru
whom I've taken in my body
新たな強い自分を見つけるよ。
and find my new, powerful self.
ぐわぁ～！　うわっ！
うわぁ～！！
なんだ…　サソリだと思ったのに→
What? I thought you were Sasori...
サソリのおばあさんでしたか。
But you're his grandmother.
THE GREAT NARUTO BRIDGE
鬼人　桃地再不斬。
The demon... Zabuza Momochi...
再び　忍刀七人衆として
働いてもらうよ。
Carry on once again as one of
the Seven Ninja Swords Men
of the Mist.
ASUMA SARUTOBI
DAN KATO
HAYATE GEKKO
SUKEZO YAMAMOTO JOUTA MISHINA
うっ…　ぐあ～っ！！
キミが　山椒魚の半蔵？
You're Hanzo of the Salamander?
い…　いや…
俺は　半蔵様の右腕の右腕。
N-No, I'm the right-hand man
of his right-hand man...
雨宿りのヘイジ。
Heiji of the Rain Shelter...
FIRE TEMPLE
ぐわぁ！
キミが　守護忍十二士の地陸？
You are Chiriku of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve?
いや　拙僧は地陸の師匠の
中覚というものじゃ。
No. I am Chiriku's mentor, Chukaku.
へぇ　地陸より強いのかい？
Oh, you're stronger than Chiriku?
いや　拙僧は学問の師匠じゃよ。
No, I am merely a scholar.
(フウ…))
ホント　失敗作をいくつも作った。
What a motley crew of failures.
でも　使い道はあったね。
Still, I have use for them.
やれやれだ。
Good grief...
これで全部？
わからない。
This is all of them?
I don't know...
煙に紛れて
逃げ出したヤツがいるかも。
Maybe some escaped
under cover of the smoke.
本部へ連絡しろ。　封印した
穢土転生忍者を狙われた。
Contact HQ.
Tell them that they were targeting
the sealed Reanimated Ninja.
他は大丈夫か？　と。
Ask if the others are safe...
見えたぞ。　あれだ！
I see it. Over there!
（テマリ）急げ。
我愛羅の本隊と合流するぞ。
Hurry! We must rendezvous
with Gaara's Main Company!
（マツリ）テマリさん　本部より連絡です。
大至急　Ｕターンです！
Temari! A message from HQ!
We must turn back immediately!
なんだ？
What?!
あの中に　三代目雷影ってのが
封印されてんのか。
Someone known as the Third Raikage
is sealed in there.
要するに
あれを復活させろってんだろ？
I guess that means
we're supposed to resurrect him.
任せろ！
Leave it to me!
うわ～っ！！
TRAP
結界だ。
土遁　砂踊り！
It's a barrier.
Earth Style: Sand Dance!
結界は消したが…。
The barrier is broken, but...
こっちは取れねえ。
I can't undo this.
ずいぶん頑固な術式じゃねえか。
It's a stubborn Jutsu Formula,
isn't it?
（トルネ）まず
その術式を解かなければ。
First, we have to decode
that Jutsu Formula.
（中覚）では　拙僧の出番じゃな。
Well then, it's my turn...
やりたくはないが…。
できんの？
Although I have
no desire to do this.
But can you do it?
術式なら　むしろ
わしら　坊主の得意分野じゃ。
Jutsu Formulas fall under
the expertise of we priests.
はっ！
おっ！　やるな　坊さん。
Hey, not bad, priest!
斬り斬り舞の術！
Blade Dance Jutsu!
うわ～！
やっと封印した雷影だ。
復活など　させるものか！
It took forever to
seal the Raikage.
We're not going to
let him come back!
うぉ～！
テマリ！
えっ！？
Temari!
Huh?
会いたかったよ　テマリ！
How I've longed to see you, Temari!
えっ！？　えぇ～っ？
Huh?!
知り合い？
（ユカタ）さぁ？
She knows him?
Beats me.
ダ…　ダイマル！？
D-Daimaru?!
なんで　お前が
穢土転生されている！？
How'd you become reanimated?!
もう　こうなったら
言うしかないんで　言うぞ！
I have nothing to lose anyway,
so I'll tell you!
な…　なんだ？
W-What's that?!
ずっと　お前のことが
好きだった！
I've always loved you!
カマイタチ！
Wind Scythe!
ぐわ～！
うぅ…　まぁ　しようがねえか。
Oh well, it can't be helped.
穢土転生なんだからな。
After all, I'm a Reanimation.
だけど　テマリ…
俺のこと　どう思ってるか→
But Temari...
At least tell me
how you feel about me.
返事は聞かせてくれ。
っていうか　お前…　ガキの頃　私に
さんざん　いじわるしておいて→
Listen... When we were kids,
you were always mean to me.
今更　なんだと！？
And you tell me this now?
（ダイマル）いや　あれは…　悪かった！
Oh well... I'm sorry about back then.
死んだ今なら　言える。
お前のことが気になって…。
But I'm dead, so I can tell you.
You were always on my mind.
なんで　それで　いじわるだ？
Then why were you so mean?!
まぁ　まぁ！
テマリさん　しかたがないですよ。
Aw c'mon, Temari,
it can't be helped...
男の子なんて　そんなものです。
そんなもの？
Boys are like that.
Like what?
そうなんです。
でも　ステキですね　テマリさん！
Like that.
I think it's beautiful, Temari.
死んでなお　思いのたけを
告げにくる人がいるなんて…。
There's someone who wants to
declare his love for you...
More so, now that he's dead.
ロマンチック！
ア…　アイツが穢土転生されただけだ！
It's so romantic.
It's only because
he's been reanimated.
しかし　よく　お前が
穢土転生されたな。
Actually, I'm surprised
that you were.
そりゃ　赤い砂塵のダイマル様だもの！
Hey, I'm Daimaru
the Red Cloud of Dust.
Ｃランクの任務中に死んだ
お前の通り名は→
Like the unremarkable
C-rank mission
where you lost your life,
your name is unknown.
全然　広まっていないぞ。
テマリ…　俺のこと　嫌いだったか？
Temari... Did you hate me?
いや…　風影の娘　我愛羅の姉
そういうことを→
No.
It was fun being around someone
who wasn't intimidated
まったく気にしないお前は
一緒にいて　楽だったよ。
by me being
the Kazekage's daughter
or the older sister of Gaara...
じゃ…　じゃあ　俺が生きていたら
つきあってくれた？
Then... Then had I lived,
would you have gone out with me?
いや　ないな。　それは　ない。
Nope. No way. No way.
お前のそういう　きっぱりしたとこ
やっぱ　好きだ…。
Damn, you're so honest.
I like that about you.
テマリさんには彼氏いますから。
えっ？
Temari already has
someone she likes.
知性派ですから。
やっぱ　そうか！
Yup, an intelligent guy.
I figured so...
いや　ないから！　誰もいないから。
No, I don't! There's no one!
じゃあ　そろそろ　封印してくれ。
Okay, better seal me.
お前が死んだと聞いたときは
悲しかったな。
When I heard you had died,
I was sad.
こうして会えたのも　何かの縁か。
Seeing you now must be fate.
泣いた？　なぁ　泣いた？
Did you cry?
Tell me, did you cry for me?
いや　泣きはしなかったな。
No... I didn't cry.
（ダイマル）封印班！　早くしろ。
お…　おう。
Sealing Team!
Make it snappy!
R-Right.
じゃあな　テマリ。
So long, Temari.
じゃあな　ダイマル。
So long, Daimaru...
さて！
Now then...
気をつけろ。　ダンゾウの護衛に
ついていた　木ノ葉の根だ。
Be careful.
He belonged to
the Leaf's Foundation
and was Danzo's bodyguard.
使い手のはず。
He must be strong.
知ってのとおり
命令には逆らえない。
As you know...
we cannot defy our orders.
だから　俺には近づくな。
Therefore, stay away from me.
斬り斬り舞の術！
Blade Dance Jutsu!
分身の術！？
本部に　ヤツのことを伝えろ。
Was that a Clone Jutsu?
Notify HQ about him.
私たちは本隊と合流する。
（２人）は～い。
We're going to rendezvous
with the Main Company.
– Right!
（カブト）取られた駒は
取り返せなかったが…。
We couldn't retrieve
the pawns we lost...
拾いものだね　この駒。
But this pawn has turned out
to be quite a find...
早く　俺を封印しろ。
Hurry up and seal me...
or you'll be destroyed!
このままでは　全滅するぞ。
I was tired of walking and didn't know what I should do
aruki tsukarete tohou ni kureta
my teacher told me to go towards a bright future
akarui mirai e sensei wa iu kedo
but which way should I go to find the light?
docchi ni aruitara hikari wa sasu kana
I have no idea at the moment so let's go
toriaezu wakaranai kedo ikouze
don't tell me things I want to hear
kirei goto nanka maji kan kanben desu
just give me something so powerful that it hurts
itai kurai tsuyoi yatsu wo choudai
I'm rebelling against the ordinary life
arikitari na mainichi ni hankou desu
burning up the mic with our rock
tagire m i c oretachi no rock
I can hear you are screaming
kimino koe ga kikoeru
that's the only thing that's real, let it explode
sore dake wa real sa hajikero
this song
kono uta
i can hear you are screaming
I'm running through the night on impulse
tsuki ugokasare shoudou no mama ni yoru wo kakenda
can't you see can't you see can't you see my face
I want to sense this moment not just the words, I want to sense you
kotoba ja nai ima dake wo kanjitetai kimi wo kanjitetai
i can hear you are screaming
keep on shouting and open the door to tomorrow
sakebi tsuzukete ashita no tobira wo kojihirakerunda
don't worry don't worry don't worry baby
I want to believe in us, not anyone else, I want to believe in my dream
dareka ja nai oretachi wo shinjitetai yume wo shinjitetai
Next Episode
Good job finding me...
My beetles notified me.
Based on your appearance,
it seems you were reanimated...
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Do you remember
my Venomous Beetles?
美空ひばりです。
Hurry and call for reinforcements.
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
You won't be able to
stop me by yourself.
No, I'm the only one who can stop you.
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Shino vs. Torune!"
Shino vs. Torune!
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→
As insect users,
let's settle this just between us!